<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Daniel's Blog</title>
	<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/atom.xml" rel="self" />
	<updated>2025-08-21T13:56:58Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>Daniel Hughes</name>
	</author>
	<id>https://barf.btxx.org,2024-01-19:default-atom-feed/</id>
	<entry>
		<title>Youtube</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Youtube&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-11-07&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love youtube. It is probably my biggest activity. Like if you tracked everything I did that&#39;s not sleeping or eating then Youtube would be at the top. And I don&#39;t think that&#39;s super bad or a sign of the downfall of civilization. But I&#39;ve changed how I consume Youtube recently and I want to share why.
I&#39;ve watch a lot of videos about how you brain is a dopamine addicted addicted who only needs to use one more app, program, mediation technique, or some other snake oil thingamabob. The reality of it is that the only way I will stop watching youtube is that I stop going on the internet, cuz like what else is there? Yeah I read some lobste.rs posts or checking my emails, but that&#39;s not entertainment. I watch youtube the same way I use to watch tv. The relative ease and conveniency of youtube is much different than tv, but it basically the same. I do get a lot out of my youtube watching, and I&#39;ve learned that I will never get rid of it, but I have found ways to use youtube a healthy way.
Now I should mention that I have a nebula subscription and I like to browse that sometimes, but the platform is not trying for you to stay for hours on end, and as of right now the creator size is relatively small.&lt;br /&gt;  
First let&#39;s talk about not youtube. I have an instagram and reddit account, I don&#39;t have the app on my phone. I have tried and succeeded in removing them from my daily habits. To anyone who also wants to get rid of those habits I would recommend deleting the app, and installing &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a app blocker but an app &lt;em&gt;redirector&lt;/em&gt;. Redirect where? to youtube! I still have a tick of typing &#39;re&#39; when I open firefox because it used to like to reddit but now is kind of a horribly inefficient way to get to youtube(in fact I just added a youtube bookmark with &#39;re&#39; as a bookmark shortcut which you can do in firefox). I have tried with website blockers but they just don&#39;t work, this way your still occupied, and are less likely to use reddit or another program that is worse than youtube.
Now about youtube, I like enhancer for youtube as you can change the speed from 0.1 to &amp;gt;2 speed up for youtube videos which is just really nice. You might be expecting this but I use &#39;UnTrap for youtube&#39;. Which lets you customize the ui. The most important setting you must change is &lt;strong&gt;removing thumbnails&lt;/strong&gt;. It has helped not be sucked into a doom scroll. The second most important setting is removing recommendations, and redirecting from the home page to your subscriptions. I grew up when youtube subscriptions got less and less important in favor of the &lt;strong&gt;the algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;tm&lt;/sup&gt;, however I&#39;ve started building up a large subscription list, because when you don&#39;t have recommendations the only way to watch videos is to subscribe to people crazy right?.
There&#39;s also other stuff you can adjust with Untrap, like youtube shorts but I won&#39;t get to deep into my config options. I think having no thumbnails and also curating a good list of channels make youtube a more health platform not only for me but also for other channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025-02-25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just watched this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QEJpZjg8GuA&quot;&gt;Algorithms are breaking how we think&lt;/a&gt; by Technology Connections. &quot;Algorithmic Complacency&quot; is a great word for it. But I totally had the idea first. :P&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Youtube"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Youtube</id>
		<updated>2024-11-07T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-11-07T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Website Plans</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Website Plans&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-03-28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

A todo list if you will, taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2024/02/19/personal-website-ideas/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt; If you don&#39;t have one already, set up a website! You can use any website making tool you want. WordPress, micro.blog, omg.lol are three of many tools that you can use without code or extensive setup. You can even make your own site with code, if you want &lt;/s&gt;  Note: I used barf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a blog post about:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something that interests you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something that brought you joy recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A thing you learned over the last week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your thoughts on a book you finished reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your strategy on playing a game you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or whatever else you would like to write about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share a recipe you made recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Publish a photo you took recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/blogroll&quot;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt; that links to personal websites you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;s&gt;Make a robots.txt file that limits how search engines and AI crawlers can ingest your site.&lt;/s&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create a shrine about something that makes you happy (a band, a television show, or anything else).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make an image map that lets someone click on parts of an image to learn more. Perhaps you could make an image map of your desk where someone can click on each object to learn more about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Share a list of your favourite books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a movie recommendations page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add a dark mode that readers can enable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;s&gt;Register a domain name and use it with your website.&lt;/s&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add an easter egg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/guestbook&quot;&gt;guestbook&lt;/a&gt; where people can leave notes saying they liked your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add a background image to your website or a page on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create a scavenger hunt where people need to hunt through pages to find clues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Leave comments in your HTML so people can understand how different templates on your site work. For example, you could annotate your &lt;code&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; tag so people looking at the code know what different meta tags do. Remember, someone may be &lt;code&gt;view-source&lt;/code&gt;ing your website who has never made a website before!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Share a list of web pages (articles, websites, blog posts, photos, games, etc.) you have enjoyed recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add alt text to images that don&#39;t have them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Use WAVE to find potential accessibility issues on different pages on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;s&gt;Use PageSpeed Insights to check the speed of your website. Try to make pages load faster if they currently load slow.&lt;/s&gt;
	* Rated 99 out of 100 on performance (although there&#39;s not a lot of content yet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; If you publish academic works on your website, add a section that shows how people should cite your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make an antilibrary where you list the books you own but have not or do not plan to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a word game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write about something you added to your website (#sitedocumentation!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a list of words you learned recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;s&gt;Add an RSS feed so people can subscribe to your blog.&lt;/s&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create an &quot;on this day&quot; feature that links to blog posts you published on a given day in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add a skip link to make it easier for screen reader users to navigate your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create an archive page that lists all of the posts on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create a mascot for your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add an 88x31 button to your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://hekate2.github.io/buttonmaker/&quot;&gt;Make an 88x31 button&lt;/a&gt; for your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Join a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/webring&quot;&gt;webring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Translate a page on your website in another language you know or are learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add a &lt;a href=&quot;https://petermolnar.net/article/how-to-make-a-print-css/&quot;&gt;print stylesheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make sure all the links work on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Start a blog carnival where you challenge friends to write about a specific topic each month. Pass on the task of choosing a topic to a new person every month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://microformats.org/wiki/rel-me&quot;&gt;rel=me links&lt;/a&gt; to your other profiles on the web. Mastodon shows your website as verified with a green checkmark if your site has a rel=me link to your Mastodon profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make an &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubenerd.com/omake/&quot;&gt;Omake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; If you want to present your work professionally on your website, add a resume page, written in HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Style code snippets in posts on your blog with a syntax highlighter (i.e. Prism.js).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Review your &lt;code&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; tag contents to review scripts and tags you no longer need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a search feature for your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nownownow.com&quot;&gt;now page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/sparkline&quot;&gt;sparkline&lt;/a&gt; that shows your post frequency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Experiment with different fonts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make sure your heading sizes are not too close together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asterism_(typography&quot;&gt;asterism&lt;/a&gt;) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fleuron_(typography&quot;&gt;fleuron&lt;/a&gt;) to the end of your blog posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zachleat.com/web/youtube-embeds/&quot;&gt;lite-youtube&lt;/a&gt; web component to improve page loading speeds when you have embedded a YouTube video on the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Try a new colour scheme on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create a style page that shows how every HTML element you use to write content appears. Use this as a reference as you tweak content styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a quiz to share with your friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/Webmention&quot;&gt;Webmention&lt;/a&gt; support to your personal website so you can receive notifications when people whose sites support Webmention (like this one!) link to or write a post in response to a blog post on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_components&quot;&gt;web component&lt;/a&gt; for one of the parts on your website so that others can use that component on their website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add an effect that changes an image when you hover over it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add an audio recording of you saying your name or nickname so people know how to pronounce it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/assets/pronunciation.m4a&quot;&gt;Here&#39;s my name pronunciation recording&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/holiday_theme&quot;&gt;holiday theme&lt;/a&gt; for a day of significance for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Draw a picture and share it on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add an interactive &lt;a href=&quot;https://aaronparecki.com/&quot;&gt;pixel grid&lt;/a&gt; that people can click on your home page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add a &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notbyai.fyi/&quot;&gt;not by AI&lt;/a&gt;&quot; button if your content is all written by you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Share a list of your favourite podcasts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a new website for something you are passionate about. Baking? Poetry? Words? Funny charts? Whatever you like!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a favicon for your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a blog post about the history of your personal website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a page that has an audio recording playing in the background (birds chirping? background noise of people chatting?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a moodboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Use the &lt;code&gt;details&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;summary&lt;/code&gt; HTML elements on a page on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Change the default colour that is used to highlight text on your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Help someone else set up a website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a document that describes how your website works, for yourself (so you don&#39;t forget!). This is useful if you have made a site with code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a review of a piece of art you like. Describe how it makes you feel or what it makes you think about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a blog post with a friend about a shared interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Update an old blog post you wrote that you know needs updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://gwern.net/sidenote&quot;&gt;sidenotes&lt;/a&gt; to a blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Make a table of contents for a long article you have written.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add an icon next to external links using CSS so people know a link will take them to another site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/hovercard&quot;&gt;hovercards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Website Plans"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Website Plans</id>
		<updated>2024-03-28T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-03-28T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Please Make D.C. a state already</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Please Make D.C. a state already&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-05-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m from Washington State, but see how I had to specify &quot;state&quot; instead of saying Washington. I hate reading &quot;from Washington&quot; only to discover that the author is implying Washington D.C. I don&#39;t care if we will have an odd number of stars on the flag. It doesn&#39;t matter what its name is, although it will probably be name Lincoln or Jefferson. Also it will be funny if The Washington Post will not match the name of where its based out of.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Please Make D.C. a State Already"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Please Make D.C. a State Already</id>
		<updated>2024-05-12T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-05-12T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Please Dont Save Powerpoints as PDFs</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Please Dont Save Powerpoints as PDFs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025-06-03&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omg I just downloaded a powerpoint with what should be maybe 30-40 slides, the pdf was 223 pages. Please remove the animations or just save it as a .pptx files.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Please Dont Save Powerpoints as PDFs"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Please Dont Save Powerpoints as PDFs</id>
		<updated>2025-06-03T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2025-06-03T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>No Car, No Comp</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;No Car, No Comp&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-07-21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently got a teaching job in Seattle. I found that the company does not compensate for commute time if you take public transportation. there reasoning is:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructors can spend their public transport time engaging in other activities, unlike if they were in a car. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which I hate because its discriminating based on if I can afford a car or not. I currently do not own a car. In there guidelines for getting compensated they always use &quot;commute by car&quot;. My thought is, since I ride a bike could I get compensated because I am not able to do other things when riding a bike. I would need the place to be 30 mins away to meet the requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/No car, no Comp"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/No car, no Comp</id>
		<updated>2024-07-21T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-07-21T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>I should have seen it coming</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;I should have seen it coming&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-11-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in a clip of silicon valley there&#39;s a piece of code that has a youtube link. Naively trying to follow it I found it was a rick roll. I&#39;m done.
link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HcXu4_K1tMQ&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/I should have seen it coming"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/I should have seen it coming</id>
		<updated>2024-11-11T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-11-11T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Going Grocery Shopping on a Bicycle</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Going Grocery Shopping on a Bicycle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025-01-16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve got a car. I had a car for about 4 months now, and I never drive it. For reference I&#39;m currently in college in seattle. Its so easy to take a bus or use the light rail to get places, and I didn&#39;t have a car for three years. The only time I was in a car was to go skiing on the weekends in winter. Even then it wasn&#39;t my car it was someone else&#39;s, and the only reason I got one was so I could be that person carpooling my friends up to the mountain. 
Getting groceries are a challenge without a car. Most grocery stores are not pandering for people to walk or bike to, even in seattle. My local QFC has one single bike rack, and I could probably tie 5 bikes to it. But compare that to the parking lot right next to it with 100-200 spots, like wtf. Anyways the bike rack never files up so it doesn&#39;t really matter.
I think going grocery shopping with a bike is a better experience that with a car. For one I buy less because I can only fit so much in a 40 litre backpack (I recommend a hiking backpack from rei). I also don&#39;t drink as much milk anymore because hauling a gallon or half gallon of milk is awful.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Going Grocery Shopping on a Bicycle"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Going Grocery Shopping on a Bicycle</id>
		<updated>2025-01-16T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2025-01-16T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>First Post</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;First Post&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-03-28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first post to test if Barf is working&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/First Post"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/First Post</id>
		<updated>2024-03-28T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-03-28T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Feeling out of Place</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Feeling out of Place&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-04-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often find myself visiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dictionaryofobscuresorrows.com/&quot;&gt;The dictionary of Obscure Sorrows&lt;/a&gt; which I probably found from some post on r/InternetIsBeautiful. I really relate to some of the words on there. But the site doesn&#39;t have a function to look at random words, so I&#39;m always scrolling past words I&#39;ve looked at before. There are 119 pages, and I don&#39;t want to scroll for that long. I want to express a feeling that I think would have a definition on the dictionary.
I when to a Blues Traveler concert this weekend, and was granted backstage access because I knew someone who was related to someone in the band. I really like Blues Traveler, and I was so anxious walking around behind the stage. Super great experience and I even meet some members of the band. Anyways while doing all of this I had the worst &quot;feeling of out of place&quot;-ness. Like the only reason I&#39;m here is because I just knew someone, and I didn&#39;t feel like I deserved this treatment, similar to an impostor syndrome. I was displacing time in these artist lives that I felt like I shouldn&#39;t have been. Why should they even know me? It kind of like how celebrities talk about if they gave every fan their full attention then they wouldn&#39;t have enough time in the day. And here I am taking up what would be an extremely expensive experience for free. Kind of like if you have a para-social relationship, but you actually get to meet the person. But I am so happy that I got to be their anyways. I wish I knew of a word to describe this feeling. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Feeling out of place"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Feeling out of place</id>
		<updated>2024-04-12T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-04-12T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Book Reading Part 1</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Book Reading Part 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025-07-21
I wanted to read more books since I got a kindle so I compiled a list of books to read. Here is the first part of that list. Spoiler warning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brave New World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;88,976 Words
Quick Summary: Everyone is grow as test tube babies. No mothers just straight out of the tube. A single egg is cloned upwards of like a thousand times, and the clones are all given chemicals to edit their body and personality(Including making them dumber). Everyone reveres Henry Ford like a god and even say &quot;Oh Ford&quot; instead of &quot;Oh God&quot;. Everyone takes a concoction of drugs called Soma that is told as this perfect happiness pill. Theirs a reservation on the west cost of the united states for native americans. A dude from the &quot;
civilized&quot; society goes and finds a dude, who they call the &quot;Savage&quot;, there and takes him out of the reservation and basically parades him around.  Eventually the Savage gets super grossed out and tries to destroy some Soma. Finally the Savage tries to live a life alone in the English countries side. Some people find him whipping himself and a crowd of people rush to see this. He hangs himself at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book would be good if it didn&#39;t advocate for eugenics. There a whole story about how an island is populated with &quot;alphas&quot; and the island could not function because they need more obedient people to do all the work. It just straight up advocates for having distinct social classes were everyone dresses the same based on their class. I shouldn&#39;t even be surprised, I knew going into the book that Henry Ford was treated like a god which show the authors ideals.
I think that the idea of Soma could draw parallels to modern day technology use, but it not really worth it. The moral of the story was don&#39;t try to be special and conform to society as much as possible. If you can&#39;t go live in the woods or on an island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;136,800 Words
Writing this fresh after reading it. That ending is very pathetic, but the book is very good. I know there is more books in the series apparently, but I am assuming that&#39;s it. 
Anyways I found the content of the book to flip flop between very violent and very boring. That first rape of Elisabeth, in my opinion, came out of no where. I guess I should have been expecting it because its a &quot;physiological thriller&quot;, but I was reading it on a kindle, and I downloaded it without reading the description.
What I liked was the build up of the mystery of what happened to Harriet. I think when he first found the lead of the photo of Harriet, I was finally happy something had happened. However, now I relies that I the author was really good at building up the characters and environment before everything that happened after. 
Good god was it a long book.
&lt;h1&gt;Catch-22&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;143,601 Words
Reading Now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Book Reading Part 1"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Book Reading Part 1</id>
		<updated>2025-07-21T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2025-07-21T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Blank Major is a Ponzi Scheme</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Blank Major is a Ponzi Scheme&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025-05-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard this yesterday from an amath major talking about pure math. I&#39;ve heard this online about almost every major, but most of it is at the humanities. I think this is some real stupid shit. It promotes anti-intellectualism. Can&#39;t we just learn things for the sake of learning things? If a person has a real interest in learning Latin even though its a dead language they should still go for it. Good things do come out of people learning a dead language. Certain (conservative) people think that a major has to be useful to be valuable. We don&#39;t need things to have a purpose to learn about them. Just because engineering can make shit doesn&#39;t make English majors any less important. Honestly majors like psychology are more important that aerospace engineering because they&#39;re not about to go off and design missiles.
Anyone who says stuff like this is trying to demoralize people about higher education. Learning stuff is good.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Blank Major is a Ponzi Sceme"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Blank Major is a Ponzi Sceme</id>
		<updated>2025-05-19T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2025-05-19T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Anime List</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Anime List&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-07-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AoT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10
No description needed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code Geass&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8/10
I feel like this anime suffers from the same trope as Death Note. Lelouch is just portrayed as a smart character, but I didn&#39;t see alot of super smart stuff. Playing chess is not a sign of a super genius. Also the Euphemia thing was horribly written. Just read a tl;dr and learn about the ending for cultural clout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Darling in the Franxx&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6/10
Evangelion nostalgia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Death Note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8/10
Pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dr. Stone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9/10
Love me some science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6/10
Love me a good harem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Highschool DxD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8/10
Love me some boobies. Can&#39;t believe it got four seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In Another World with my Smartphone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/10
Lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kill la Kill&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10
Such a great funny anime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Made in Abyss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10
the mangaka needs to get his shit together and finish this before he dies. Can&#39;t believe he is color blind. Nanachi and Faputa is so cute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mushoku Tensei&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10
Great world building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evangelion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10 
Require reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;No Game, No Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7/10
The more I look back the less I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;One Punch Man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10
Require reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ranking of Kings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8/10
some superb animation and story. Pacing is awful, you had 23 episodes and that&#39;s it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saga of Tanya the Evil&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6/10 
Nazi role play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Steins;Gate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8/10
Probably revolutionary for a time travel story in 2011, probably could have gone more extreme. The microwave explanation is stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The World&#39;s Finest Assassin Gets Reincarnated in Another World as an Aristocrat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6/10 
LEGALIZE NUCLEAR BOMBS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wonder Egg Priority&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8/10
Sad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Deadman Wonderland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfinished
I tried watch this anime twice. Just couldn&#39;t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kabaneri of the Iron Fortress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfinished
Attack on Titan -esqe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chainsaw Man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unwatch
Read the manga. Waiting for the anime to release the reze arc to watch. Power best girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dungeon Meshi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10
Bestest world building, great character design. love trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I Was Reincarnated as the 7th Prince so I Can Take My Time Perfecting My Magical Ability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/10
Isekai trash. Is this rated as a kids show because that&#39;s the animation quality I was getting, but also very sexual for a kids show. Who is this for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;As a Reincarnated Aristocrat, I&#39;ll Use My Appraisal Skill to Rise in the World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfinished
Horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solo Leveling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/10
Finished the anime went and read the manga. No story. The main character almost never struggles, and never fails. Could catch up with the manga because it was just the same loop of fight and get way stronger than before. near the end I was just so confused by why I was even reading the manga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mashle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7/10
Anime Harry Potter without the transphobia. Not great. The thought that the main character doesn&#39;t have any magic abilities is amazing, but they never have a better solution besides &quot;Punch the problem even harder than before&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Undead Unluck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9/10
Absurd plot that I like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Great Pretender&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/10
you should go watch this one. Love Trigger.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/Anime List"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/Anime List</id>
		<updated>2024-07-19T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-07-19T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>AI Voice</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;AI Voice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-09-13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My highschool freshman english teacher said something about my writing that I think a lot about. He discussed how each person has a voice in their writing, and that he can tell whose paper he is reading by the voice in the words. I often think about my own voice, and how its changed as I&#39;ve grown up, or how it changes when I write texts, emails, or papers. 
The thing that scared my the most is when my teacher said that he could tell if someone else help us write our paper because the voice of the words changed. Relating to AI I think that if someone uses AI to write the the voice of that writing must change. There was a study done on research papers that found the use of &quot;delve&quot; to be higher in newer papers because chat-gpt uses &quot;delve&quot; more frequently because it was trained on skewed data. I have completely dropped the word &quot;delve&quot; from my vocabulary because I fear that someone might use it to show that I wrote a paper with AI. 
I wonder if my english teacher can tell if someone wrote a their paper with AI.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://barf.btxx.org/AI voice"/>
		<id>https://barf.btxx.org/AI voice</id>
		<updated>2024-09-13T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-09-13T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
</feed>
